[Music]
in a review of more than a hundred
articles about the effects of cooking on
vegetables they tried to find The Sweet
Spot on one hand heat can destroy
certain nutrients on the other hand by
softening the tissues they can become
more
bioavailable researchers settled upon
steaming as the best cooking method to
preserve the most nutrition you're not
dunking it in water or oil where the
nutrients can leech out and you're not
reaching excessive dry heat temperatures
but they acknowledge that of all the
common cooking methods we know the least
about pressure cooking there's all these
fancy new electric pressure cookers on
the market including the instant pot
with more five-star ratings than even
how not to die I'm jealous these
pressure cookers are great for cooking
dried beans with just a touch of a
button but what happens to the nutrition
here's the antioxidant content of
pre-soaked black beans boiled for an
hour normally compare that to pressure
cooking for 15
minutes even more in fact six times more
wow here I was pressure cooking just
because I like the texture better the
canned ones can be a bit mushy and I was
spending lots of money on cases of
canned beans whereas dried beans are
just so Dirt Cheap so so wait so wait
cheaper tastier and healthier that's
quite a comp
okay but what about pressure cooking
vegetables vitamin C is one of the more
heat sensitive nutrients sauté spinach
or amaranth leaves in a pan for 30
minutes and about 95% of the vitamin C
is destroyed whereas 10 minutes in a
pressure cooker wiped out only about 90%
but who pressure Cooks spinach for 10
minutes and sautéing for half an hour
and even then not much effects on beta
carotene levels either way vitamin C is
but one of many antioxidants what about
the effects of pressure cooking on
overall antioxidant capacity here's the
cooking methods they compared uh so for
the carrots for example 12 minutes of
boiling compared to 5 minutes of
pressure cooking compared to 6 minutes
of
microwaving here's what they found
cooking carrots increased their
antioxidant potential in fact pressure
cooking nearly doubled their antioxidant
value whereas peas took a hit no matter
how they were cooked I'm particularly
interested in the greens uh the chard
wasn't affected much across the board
but microwaving beat out pressure
cooking and boiling for the spinach note
that pressure cooking beat out the
boiling too though and pressure cooking
is boiling just at a shorter time and a
higher temperature but the time appeared
to Trump the temperature significantly
less nutrient loss pressure cooking
spinach for 3 and 1 half minutes
compared to Boiling for eight same for
those magical cancer finding
glucosinolate compounds in cruciferous
greens the healthiest greens like you
know kale cards and turnup greens here's
where level started out raw with 3/4
wiped out by boiling but less than half
with pressure cooking now both got beat
by steaming but that's because you
weren't dunking The Greens in water
which can leech out the nutrients but
even though the pressure cooked greens
were immersed just as much as the boiled
greens only half the nutrient losses
presumably because it was only half the
time 7 Minutes pressure cooked compared
to 15 minutes boiled okay so here's my
idea this was after 10 minutes of
steaming what if you cut down that time
by pressure steaming uh like put a layer
of water down at the bottom of an
electric pressure cooker drop in a metal
steaming basket on top and then put the
greens in and steam Under Pressure uh
that's how I cook the greens I eat every
day I've always loved collards in like
southern cooking or Ethiopian cuisine
and I found I could get that same melt
iny mouth texture just steaming under
pressure for zero minutes what you do is
set for zero so it shuts off as soon as
it reaches the cooking pressure and then
quick release valet immediately to
release the steam the greens turn out
perfect bright emerald green cooked
tender give it a try and let me know
what you think
[Music]